<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Template: (9 lines)
  <problem>
    <name></name>
    <shortFileName></shortFileName>
    <id></id>
    <categories>
      <category></category>
    </categories>
    <summary></summary>
  </problem>
-->
<allProblems>
  <problem>
    <name>Name that Permutation</name>
    <shortFileName>Permutation</shortFileName>
    <id>namethatpermutation</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Sequences</category>
      <category>Math</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given an integer n in the interval [1,50] and an integer k in the interval [0, n!-1] find the kth permutation of the first n positive integers.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Page Layout</name>
    <shortFileName>Page</shortFileName>
    <id>pagelayout</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Complete search</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a set of up to 20 rectangles, determine the largest area covered by a subset of these rectangles such that no pair of rectangles in the subset overlap.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Fleecing the Raffle</name>
    <shortFileName>Raffle</shortFileName>
    <id>raffle</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Combinatorics</category>
      <category>Probability</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>In a raffle in which n people have entered their names and there are p prizes to be won, determine the number of times that you should enter your name to maximise your probability of winning exactly one prize.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Taxi Cab Scheme</name>
    <shortFileName>Taxi</shortFileName>
    <id>taxicab</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a series of taxi journeys that need to be made at specific times, determine the fewest number of taxi cabs needed to satisfy all journeys without delay.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Stock Prices</name>
    <shortFileName>Stock</shortFileName>
    <id>stockprices</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Ad hoc</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a series of bids for stocks and sell offers and a mechanism for establishing deals following bid and sell offers, determine after each bid and sell offer the current asking price for the stock, the current bid price, and the most recent deal price.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Daydreaming Stockbroker</name>
    <shortFileName>Stock</shortFileName>
    <id>stockbroker</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given the prices of shares on different days, determine the maximum amount of money that can be made by buying and selling shares on different days.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Moogle</name>
    <shortFileName>Moogle</shortFileName>
    <id>moogle</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given some data points, and a formula for calculating the interpolation error, choose a subset of the data points such that the interpolation error for the remaining data points is minimised.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Crop Triangles</name>
    <shortFileName>Crop</shortFileName>
    <id>crophard</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Combinatorics</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a set of up to 100,000 points with integer coordinates, compute how many distinct triangles can be formed that have a centre at integer coordinates as well.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Mixing Colours</name>
    <shortFileName>Colours</shortFileName>
    <id>mixingcolours</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given an ordered list of tokens that can be any one of many possible colours with some probability and a set of rules through which adjacent tokens can be combined to make tokens of other colours, determine the most probable colour of the token that results after enough rules have been applied to reduce the original list of tokens to a single token.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Circumsphere</name>
    <shortFileName>Sphere</shortFileName>
    <id>circumsphere</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Geometry</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given 4 points in 3-space, find the centre of the sphere uniquely defined by these points.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Covered Walkway</name>
    <shortFileName>Covered</shortFileName>
    <id>coveredwalkway</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Ad hoc</category>
      <category>Sequences</category>
      <category>Geometry</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a sequence of up to 1 million points that need to be covered by a set of intervals, each with a cost equal to the square of the size of the interval plus some constant, determine the smallest cost to cover all points.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Slikar</name>
    <shortFileName>Slikar</shortFileName>
    <id>slikar</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Grids</category>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a grid that is being filled up by a flood, determine the shortest path from the starting cell to the ending cell that avoids the flood, if it is possible to find such a path.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>A Plus B Problem</name>
    <shortFileName>Plus</shortFileName>
    <id>aplusb</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Ad Hoc</category>
      <category>Combinatorics</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given an array of integers, count the number of ordered triples of distinct indices such that the sum of the 2 numbers at the first 2 indices is equal to the number at the third index.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Citadel Construction</name>
    <shortFileName>Citadel</shortFileName>
    <id>citadelconstruction</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Geometry</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a set of up to 1000 points find the set of 4 points that maximises the area of the quadrilateral that they define.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Polly Gone</name>
    <shortFileName>Polly</shortFileName>
    <id>pollygone</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a number of boxes each with an amount of energy required to open them and a probability of finding a parrot in that box, find the smallest amount of energy required to find the parrot with at least some given probability.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Chasing the Cheetahs</name>
    <shortFileName>Cheetahs</shortFileName>
    <id>cheetahs</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Ad Hoc</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given the start times and speeds of a set of cheetahs running in a straight line, find the smallest distance that occurs between the furthest ahead cheetah and the furthest behind cheetah.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Coloring</name>
    <shortFileName>Coloring</shortFileName>
    <id>coloring</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
      <category>Complete Search</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a graph determine the minimum number of colours required such that all vertices are coloured and no edge has 2 vertices that are the same colour.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Frogger</name>
    <shortFileName>Frogger</shortFileName>
    <id>frogger</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a 2D grid that a frog can move in through lanes of traffic travelling in alternating directions, determine if the frog can make it to the other side of the road.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Darts</name>
    <shortFileName>Darts</shortFileName>
    <id>darts</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>For a game of darts between 2 players employing different strategies, find the probability that each player will win when they go first from a particular starting score.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Bag of Tiles</name>
    <shortFileName>Bag</shortFileName>
    <id>bagoftiles</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a collection of tiles with a number on each, a target value, and a number, n, determine how many ways n of the tiles can sum to the target value.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Shuffling Along</name>
    <shortFileName>Shuffling</shortFileName>
    <id>shuffling</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Determine the number of times required to shuffle a deck of n cards to return them to their original order.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Boastin' Red Socks</name>
    <shortFileName>RedSocks</shortFileName>
    <id>redsocks</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Math</category>
      <category>Complete Search</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a drawer of an unknown number of socks that are either red or black, and the probability of pulling out a pair of red socks, calculate the number of red and black socks in the drawer.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Factors</name>
    <shortFileName>Factors</shortFileName>
    <id>factors</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Math</category>
      <category>Combinatorics</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>For a given number, n, calculate the smallest value such that the number of distinct permutations of the multiplicands of the value's prime factorisation is n.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Assembly Line</name>
    <shortFileName>Assembly</shortFileName>
    <id>assemblyline</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given multiple sequences of letters and a set of production rules with associated costs for transforming adjacent letters into other letters, find the minimum cost of transofmring the entire sequence into a single letter.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Three-State Memory</name>
    <shortFileName>Memory</shortFileName>
    <id>memory</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
      <category>Combinatorics</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a binary representation of a number, compute the number of equivalent represenations using an augmented binary system that allows `2's.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Decoding the Hallway</name>
    <shortFileName>Hallway</shortFileName>
    <id>decodingthehallway</id>
    <categories>
      <category>String manipulation</category>
      <category>Ad hoc</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given a recurrence relation that describes an interative process through which a string is constructed, determine if a given string is a substring of the string constructed after n iterations of applying the recurrence relation.</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Comparing Answers</name>
    <shortFileName>Answers</shortFileName>
    <id>comparinganswers</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Graph Theory</category>
      <category>Matrices</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given the number of roads of length 1 between each pair of cities, verify a calculation of the number of paths of length 2 between each pair of cities</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Divisors</name>
    <shortFileName>Divisors</shortFileName>
    <id>divisors</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Math</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given integers n, k, compute the number of divisors of nCk (n Choose k)</summary>
  </problem>
  <problem>
    <name>Liga</name>
    <shortFileName>Liga</shortFileName>
    <id>liga</id>
    <categories>
      <category>Dynamic Programming</category>
    </categories>
    <summary>Given some incomplete information about wins, draws, losses, games played, and points in a football league table, determine the missing values.</summary>
  </problem>
</allProblems>
